technojobs.co.uk 2018-09-01

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Technojobs Ltd is an award-winning company operating in the online recruitment market. Our web platform promotes over 10,000 jobs each month and empowers some of the UK’s leading companies to recruit the very best staff they need.  Our services are business centric and as such our collection and processing of candidate personal data is in regard to the fulfilment of our business aims.

We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we take that very seriously. This Privacy Notice describes Technojobs Ltd policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data and sets forth your privacy rights. We recognise that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from time to time update this Privacy Notice as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.

Technojobs has also created a candidate FAQ for GDPR which you can [read here](https://www.technojobs.co.uk/gdpr-faq.phtml).

## Data Protection Officer / Contacts 

Technojobs Ltd is headquartered in the United Kingdom. Technojobs Ltd have not appointed an internal data protection officer as our processing is not of a type or scale that requires one. However, should you have any questions or concerns about Technojobs Ltd personal data policies or practices; you can reach out to us at the following address:  

TechnoJobs Ltd  
50 Broadway  
London   
SW1H 0RG 

Telephone: 0203 151 4024  
Email: [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk)  
Company Number: 05452221

We always respond to data enquiries and will investigate or clarify any requests. If there are any questions we encourage you to get in touch with us so we can respond accordingly. 

## How we collect and use (process) your personal information

## 1 - Personal information you give to us:

  1. **Corporate Customers** When you become a customer of Technojobs Ltd, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your employer’s name, your work address (including your country location), telephone number and your email address. 

We process your personal information under the General Data Protection Regulations Article (6)(b) in order to provide you with the product / service you have purchased, undertake standard business functions such as billing, and to inform you of relevant events, content, and other benefits or opportunities. Technojobs Ltd may also process this information under the General Data Protection Regulations Article (6)(f) to help us understand our customers’ needs and interests, to better tailor our products and services to meet those needs.

**Registered Users – Candidates**

When you become a registered user of Technojobs.co.uk, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your location, your email address and a copy of your CV. 

We process your personal information under the General Data Protection Regulations Article (6)(b) in order to provide you with the recruitment service you have requested. We will also process this information to undertake standard business functions such to inform you of relevant events, content, and other benefits or related opportunities. Technojobs Ltd may also process this information under the General Data Protection Regulations Article (6)(f)  to help us understand our customers’ needs and interests, to better tailor our products and services to meet those needs. 

  1. **Publications and Subscriptions**

Technojobs Ltd offers a great deal of content on our website. In addition to producing original content, Technojobs Ltd also subscribes to news feeds and blogs produced by others, which we often link to from our website. This means you may find yourself on the Technojobs Ltd website or reading an email from Technojobs Ltd and we will offer you a link to another organization’s website where you will find content that we feel will be relevant and useful to you. At these times, you will be leaving the Technojobs Ltd website. Technojobs Ltd is not responsible or liable for content provided by these third-party websites or personal information they may happen to gather from you.

You may manage your subscriptions to Technojobs Ltd newsletters by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time. You can also log into your account and change preferences at any time.  If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences with Technojobs Ltd, please contact us at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk).

Technojobs Ltd uses Google Analytics to track how often people gain access to or read our content. We use this information in the aggregate to understand what content our customers find useful or interesting, so we can produce the most valuable content and services to meet your needs.

  1. **Your correspondence** **with the** **Technojobs Ltd**

If you correspond with us by email, the postal service, or other form of communication, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to your inquiry; to notify you of Technojobs Ltd services; or to keep a record of your complaint and the like. As always, if you wish to have Technojobs Ltd “erase” your personal information or otherwise refrain from communicating with you, candidates can log in and delete their account at any time. You can contact us at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk) if there are any questions or problems with this. 

  1. **Purposes for processing your data**

Technojobs Ltd processes your data to provide you or the company you work for, with the goods or services you have requested or purchased from us. We use this information to refine our goods and services to better tailor them to your needs and to communicate with you about other related services we offer that may assist your job hunting or your business. 

## 2 - Personal information we get from third parties

Technojobs Ltd does not receive personal information about individuals from third parties. 

## 3 - What happens if you don’t give us your data

You can enjoy much of the information on our website without giving us your personal data. Some personal information is necessary so that Technojobs Ltd can supply you with the recruitment services you have purchased or requested.. You may manage your Technojobs Ltd account online and you may opt-out of receiving marketing communication at any time.

## Use of the Technojobs Ltd Website

As is true of most other websites, Technojobs Ltd website collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of our website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit our users’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyse trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. Technojobs Ltd website also uses cookies, web beacons and click tracking. It does not track users when they cross to third party websites, does not provide targeted advertising to them, and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.

  * **Cookies, web beacons and click tracking**

Cookies are pieces of data that a Web site transfers to a user's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage, e-mail response and tracking. Click tracking is a means of measuring the number of clicks a particular advert/image/banner receives. 

The Site uses cookies to provide enhanced functionality on the site (e.g., user ID and password prompts) and aggregate traffic data (e.g., what pages are the most popular). These cookies may be delivered in a first-party or third-party context. Technojobs Ltd may also use cookies, click tracking and web beacons in association with e-mails delivered by Technojobs Ltd. Our Site also captures limited information (user-agent, HTTP referrer, last URL requested by the user, client-side and server-side clickstream) about visits to our Site; we may use this information to analyse general traffic patterns, to perform routine system maintenance or to provide our clients with metrics related to the success of their recruitment campaign. You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purposes of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using Technojobs Ltd website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

## When and how we share information with others

**Registered Candidates:**  
When you register with Technojobs we create an account for you and store your data in one of our UK based servers. When you upload your CV, this too is processed and maintained in association with your account in one of our UK based servers. We will process your CV for the purpose of rendering it searchable by our clients, who engage with us for the purpose of recruiting staff. 

**Corporate Clients:**  
As a client of Technojobs we create an account for you and store your data in our USA based CRM system, and UK based finance system. 

**In both cases:**  
We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) it’s in connection with the recruitment services of Technojobs Ltd; (3) the information is provided to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (4) the information is provided to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (5) to address emergencies or acts of God; or (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating legal authority to act on your behalf. We may also gather aggregated data about our customers and Site visitors and disclose the results of such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to our partners, service providers, advertisers and/or other third parties for marketing or promotional purposes.  
In the course of our business to help you search and get a job, Technojobs may make personal information available to third parties such as employers and recruiters.

The Technojobs Ltd website uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to "like" or share information from the Technojobs Ltd website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.

## Transferring personal data from the EU to the US

Technojobs Ltd has its headquarters and main servers here in the United Kingdom. We also utilise the CRM services of a company located in the United States (Salesforce) to store information about our corporate clients (NOT candidate data). Information we collect from you will be processed in either the UK or the USA depending upon the product or service you have purchased from us or we are providing. The United States have not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union under Article 45 of the GDPR. Technojobs Ltd relies on the USA Privacy Shield to govern the transfer of data to the USA. In particular, Technojobs Ltd collects and transfers to the USA personal data only: with your consent; to perform a contract with you; or to fulfil a compelling legitimate interest of Technojobs Ltd in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Technojobs Ltd endeavours to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with Technojobs Ltd and the practices described in this Privacy Notice. Technojobs Ltd also minimizes the risk to your rights and freedoms by minimising the data that we collect and store about you. 

## Data subject rights 

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects. A good explanation of them (in English) is available on the website of the United Kingdom’s [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-gdpr/individuals-rights/the-right-to-be-informed/).

This Privacy Notice is intended to provide you with information about what personal data Technojobs Ltd collects about you and how it is used. If you have any questions, please contact us at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk) _._

If you wish to confirm that Technojobs Ltd is processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data we may have about you, please contact us at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk)

You may also request information about: the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal data concerned; who else outside of Technojobs Ltd might have received the data from us; what the source of the information was (if you didn’t provide it directly to us); and how long it will be stored. You have a right to correct (rectify) the record of your personal data maintained by us if it is inaccurate. You may request that we erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain exceptions. You may also request that Technojobs Ltd cease using your data for direct marketing purposes. In many countries, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how Technojobs Ltd processes your personal data. When technically feasible, Technojobs Ltd will—at your request—provide your personal data to you or transmit it directly to another controller. Much of the functionality outlined here is available to you through your Technojobs online account, which you can access by logging in to your account at www.technojobs.co.uk

Reasonable access to your personal data will be provided at no cost upon request made to Technojobs Ltd at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk). If access cannot be provided within a reasonable time frame, we will provide you with a date when the information will be provided. If for some reason access is denied, we will provide an explanation as to why access has been denied.

## Security of your information

To help protect the privacy of data and personally identifiable information you transmit through use of this Site, we maintain a range of physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We restrict access to your personal data to those employees and clients who need to know that information to provide benefits or services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees' privacy responsibilities.

## Data storage and retention

Your personal data is stored by Technojobs Ltd on its servers, and on the servers of the Customer Relationship Management Company for corporate clients (Salesforce) that we engage, located in the United States. Technojobs Ltd retains data for the duration of the users or business relationship with us. For more information on where and how long your personal data is stored, and for more information on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact our privacy officer at [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk).

## Changes and updates to the Privacy Notice 

By using this Site, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use and/or any other agreement that we might have with you. If you do not agree to any of these terms and conditions, you should not use this Site or any Technojobs Ltd services. You agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use, or any other agreement we have with you, will be governed by the laws of the United Kingdom. 

As our business changes from time to time, this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use at this Site. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and terms and conditions and will e-mail customers of material changes thereto, but you should check our Site frequently to see the current Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use that is in effect and any changes that may have been made to it. The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or statements regarding our privacy practices and the terms and conditions that govern the use of this Site.

## Children and minors

Technojobs Ltd is not at all directed towards individuals under the age of eighteen (18), however we are aware due to the nature of some of the job offerings, those between 16 and 18 may use the services.  Individuals under the age of thirteen (13) are _expressly prohibited_ from using Technojobs, unless parental consent is provided and we are notified.

## What legal basis do Technojobs rely on to process personal information?

  * Consent (this can be withdrawn at any time) 
  * To fulfil a contract  (help candidates to get a job though job applications and or sending a CV to and employer or recruiter) 
  * Legitimate interest (including relevant and tailored communications related to job seeking and selling and supplying services to our customers)  
  * Legal Obligations (to comply with any legal representations) 

## Desktop, Mobile site, Mobile App 

Note that this privacy policy is applicable to Technojobs Ltd across all devices including Desktop, the mobile site and the Technojobs App (‘IT Jobs UK’).  If you enable Technojobs, on the mobile devices, we access the following services for the limited purpose of helping us to upload or otherwise access your CV, cover letters or any other documents you provide us to assist you apply for jobs. The Services we use are: Google Cloud, OneDrive and Dropbox. 

## Questions, concerns or complaints

Please contact us at the address below:  
TechnoJobs Ltd  
50 Broadway  
London   
SW1H 0RG 

Telephone: 0203 151 4024  
Email: [support@technojobs.co.uk](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk)  
Company Number: 05452221
